<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[miraj sanghvi]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-01-13T11:11:56-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[miraj sanghvi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bold Prediction for 2018: Apple and Google PHR]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2018/01/13/bold-prediction-for-2018-apple-and-google-phr/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-13T10:53:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2018/01/13/bold-prediction-for-2018-apple-and-google-phr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the new year, comes new predictions. In an effort to better crystallize my thoughts around the future of healthcare, I&rsquo;ve been thinking about how the internet giants will continue to expand their offerings in healthcare. This line of thinking has led me to believe that Google and Apple, in 2018, will launch patient health records (PHR) embedded into iOS and Android.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As the two giants continue to play on the fringes of healthcare, I believe a bold move by one of them will push the other to enter the space shortly thereafter. Google has famously tried this experiment in the past with Google Health, which was discontinued in 2011. The idea was great, the timing wasn&rsquo;t ideal &ndash; and the interface wasn&rsquo;t where it needed to be. People didn&rsquo;t have the same trust in the internet that we have now, and most notably, smart phones weren&rsquo;t as ubiquitous. Now that everyone has a smart phone, trusting their device with highly sensitive information (including bank account access, personal pictures, search history, etc.) &ndash; I think the market is ready for health records to be stored on phones. With FHIR and interoperability across health records increasingly becoming possible, I believe Google and Apple will realize the power in the data and understand their unusual position of being at the center of a consumer&rsquo;s life &ndash; and roll out a personal health record on the device. Samsung could be a wildcard in the race, as they continue to invest heavily in healthcare.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency - a Few Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2018/01/06/cryptocurrency-a-few-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-06T09:51:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2018/01/06/cryptocurrency-a-few-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s probably thousands of posts on the subject already on the internet &ndash; and nothing said in this post should be new thoughts or information, but I&rsquo;ve found it to be helpful to write down my thoughts, forcing me to articulate my thinking on the subject. That being said &ndash; onto the post!</p>

<p>Cryptocurrency has taken the world by storm, and I, unfortunately, believe there will be a big crash in the future. Bitcoin, Ethereum, Ripple, etc. have grown in such high value, that it can&rsquo;t be sustainable (until there is a killer use-case for them).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Overall, I strongly believe in the utility of cryptocurrency and how it can change multiple industries for the better&hellip;I just don&rsquo;t believe we&rsquo;re anywhere close to that yet with bitcoin (for the remainder of this post, I&rsquo;ll use bitcoin to refer to all cryptocurrencies in the market today). I already had this thought for the past few months, but it was fully crystallized on a recent trip to NYC. There I met numerous people investing in bitcoin, not for the utility of it, but to try to make a profit in the growth in price. They were all hopeful in the utility and use-cases catching up to the currency in the future, but they had no intention of using their bitcoin&rsquo;s for anything other than an investment. That sort of thought creates an easy environment to create a bubble. Everyone believes it&rsquo;s valuable and will grow in price &ndash; but unsure of how exactly they would use the currency in their life.</p>

<p>I believe part of the thought process that is occurring around the world is FOMO. Warren Buffett has mentioned this reason as well &ndash; and to expand on that thought &ndash; I believe the recent successes of Google, Amazon, Facebook, Netflix, etc., and a majority of the financial benefits affecting a small group of individuals (early employees, VCs, and larger private growth investors) has left a lot of people feeling left out. The acknowledgment of missing that boat, and fear of potentially missing the &ldquo;bitcoin&rdquo; boat has led to a lot of investors flocking to the scene.</p>

<p>Another unsustainable part of the bitcoin process involves the energy consumption required to run the blockchain. The technology developed to run and maintain a blockchain is revolutionary. However, this initial iteration of processes required to maintain the 1st generation blockchain is way too high to be useful. The fact that it takes more energy to maintain the blockchain compared to 100s of countries is ridiculous. Perhaps a future iteration of the blockchain will be more energy-efficient, and the port over for all the current cryptocurrencies will be trivial&hellip;or a new cryptocurrency with an energy-efficient blockchain will be created and overtake the status quo. The fact that this possibility exists is enough to scare me away from bitcoin.</p>

<p>Regardless &ndash; there are too many unknowns for me to feel comfortable with the state of the market and hype around cryptocurrencies. I may miss the boat, but I think I&rsquo;ll sleep a lot better this year because I won&rsquo;t have to check coinbase on a daily basis.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Agency]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/09/20/free-agency/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-20T16:18:19-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/09/20/free-agency</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Free Agency, it&rsquo;s a normal part of sports and really a beautiful concept. The idea that after the grueling season, you get some time to talk to different teams and figure out where you might be the best fit. Although I didn&rsquo;t start this process with that mindset &ndash; I&rsquo;m starting to understand the beauty of it more and more. For some context &ndash; I recently left my role at VigLink without anything else lined up! I recently got married decided this would be a great time to change things up professionally.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The more I think about it, everyone should do a &ldquo;free agency&rdquo; period throughout their careers. Although I&rsquo;m only doing this now&hellip;after I&rsquo;ve gained enough confidence in my skills and ability to get another job when needed &ndash; it has turned out to be even more rewarding than initially imagined. The thought of constantly bouncing from one job to the next, without a clear understanding of where I wanted to be in 5 or 10 years is part of the reason that I chose to enter &ldquo;free agency&rdquo;. But one of the main driving factors was also not exactly knowing what I wanted to do next. It&rsquo;s hard enough working a full-time job and trying to interview at a couple of places&hellip;and most people (in the tech industry) rely on recruiters to reach out to them about interesting jobs. But there are so many awesome opportunities out there &ndash; and the only way to find them is through searching for them or getting connected to them through friends/acquaintances.</p>

<p>Basically the past month has been spent searching through the web for interesting companies, using AngelList and LinkedIn to make connections and setting up multiple phone chats/coffee meetings. Although it has been stressful at times, most weeks have been very rewarding! The chance to really think about the next role and imagine yourself there for 4 to 5 years is exciting. After bouncing from roles after 2 or 3 years &ndash; I&rsquo;m excited at figuring out where I&rsquo;ll land. And a great added perk has been the ability to connect with old friends and coworkers that I haven&rsquo;t chatted with in a long time. Hearing what others are up to and catching up has been one of the best ways to sort out what I want to do next &ndash; and learning about new opportunities.</p>

<p>So if you have the opportunity to take 1-2 months off of work and are thinking of changing things up professionally, I highly recommend entering free agency! It&rsquo;s a full-time job networking and interviewing, but highly rewarding.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imposter Syndrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/08/31/imposter-syndrome/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-31T11:01:46-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/08/31/imposter-syndrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Imposter Syndrome is not a new concept. You can find countless blogs and articles talking about this occurrence in software engineering as well as most specialized fields. The feeling of not knowing everything is understandable&hellip;since there is always something new out there. A new programming language, a new way to build your code, a new editor to use, etc. And it does help to know that most everyone feels this multiple times a week, helps make it easier to deal with on a regular basis.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But I like to think about it in a different way &ndash; it&rsquo;s because there is always something new to do or learn that we&rsquo;re motivated by our field. It&rsquo;s because there&rsquo;s always a new package or algorithm to learn that I&rsquo;m excited to be a data scientist. This life-long drive that we get from our profession is part of the reason we chose this path. It will provide countless years of pushing our brain and our boundaries to strive to get better. This reminds me of a talk I attended a few years ago in Philadelphia by an Oncologist &ndash; she said she constantly has to deal with this fear of doing the wrong thing with her patients. She usually has to use new techniques that aren&rsquo;t fully understood or haven&rsquo;t been mastered by her &ndash; but it&rsquo;s because she&rsquo;s always working at the cutting edge of research this will always be the case. So that feeling, however unpleasant is necessary for her to be the best doctor she can be.</p>

<p>I think that&rsquo;s very telling of this imposter syndrome and the feelings it stirs up in programmers &ndash; while it will always be there, it&rsquo;s with good reason that is occurs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journalism]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/08/23/journalism/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-23T12:30:33-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2016/08/23/journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking about Journalism a lot lately. As many are aware, the industry has been in trouble for a few years now. Readership and subscriptions are down at every local newspaper, and increased dependence on advertisements are way up. Many local newspapers have had to shut down or severely decrease their staff. This is not good for the future. Where we get our news is a strong pillar of democracy. We must be informed to be able to make wise decisions about big issues like war and pollution, as well as seemingly insignificant issues like installing a stop sign at the corner.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>While advertising is currently seen as the answer to fix journalism and make it profitable – with the likes of New York Times and The Atlantic pushing this forward – the close connection between ‘sponsored content’ and real journalism is unnerving, to say the least. When the same journalist spends the morning on a sponsored piece about how amazing Google Chrome is and the afternoon on a piece about Google and security – it’s hard to imagine unbiased reporting in either case. While this example may sound unlikely – it’s a lot closer to reality than most would believe. It’s clear to me we need to fix this, and individual paid subscriptions doesn’t seem to be the answer (not everyone is like New York Times and can command a monthly fee).</p>

<p>This isn’t an easy problem to solve, and will most likely require multiple solutions to properly fix…I do think something similar to Spotify for Journalism could prove useful. The same way artists were losing their money to illegal downloads in the 2000s, Journalism is losing money and eyes to free content. Although it requires people willing to pay for what they read – I personally would be very receptive to paying a monthly fee that directly pays the journalists of content I read. While this would still require newspapers to report on tough issues vs. popular ones – it does provide an easier method of gaining revenue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tablets]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2015/03/28/tablets/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-28T19:22:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2015/03/28/tablets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although this may seem like its been discussed a lot recently, I&rsquo;ve been thinking more and more about upgrading my iPad 2.  I recently got back from Japan, and it was great traveling without a computer &ndash; but I&rsquo;ve found that I generally only use my tablet when I travel.  And it&rsquo;s only if I don&rsquo;t have my computer with me.  The tablet was great back when my laptop&rsquo;s batteries didn&rsquo;t last as long.  But what&rsquo;s the use of them anymore?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Using the iPad as the CNS to power things in your apartment is a good use case&hellip;however I still turn to my phone more and more.  And with the increase in the size of the iPhone 6, do I even need the extra screen real-estate?  For cooking it could be nice, but only marginally.  It&rsquo;s interesting how fast that fad came and went.  The original iPad was released April, 2010 &ndash; in 5 quick years it went from the IT item to no longer relevant.  This becomes even more interesting with the upcoming release of the iWatch.  How long will smart-watches continue to be relevant.  Will they also experience a bubble like the iPad?  Or will they live on like our phones.</p>

<p>Personally, I think smart-watches are doomed to fail.  I enjoy coming home, placing my phone away and not being connected for a little bit.  With a watch, you&rsquo;re always connected.  And you always have to be connected.  The cons definitely outweigh the pros.  We&rsquo;ll see if others agree with me on this.</p>

<p>Links:</p>

<p>Tablet sales are declining <a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2015/02/02/tablet-sales-decline-for-the-first-time-in-q4-2014-but-amazon-is-hit-the-hardest">thenextweb.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Economist and UFOs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2014/06/29/economist-and-ufos/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-29T18:15:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2014/06/29/economist-and-ufos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I usually visit Economist.com a couple of times per week &ndash; generally a great place to catch up on world headlines.  Recently, I came across an article they posted about UFO sightings.  In it, they analyze data from the National UFO Reporting Centre about reported UFO sightings from the US &ndash; breaking it down by time of day.  Basically they allude that there is a peak in reported sightings during &ldquo;Drinking Hours&rdquo;.  While I agree most sightings (if not all) do require some added influence of some sort (i.e. alcohol) &ndash; there are confounding variables that may also lead to increased sightings in the evenings.  A few additional reasons include &ndash;</p>

<ul>
<li>During Working Hours, most people are indoors and busy</li>
<li>It is easier to spot things in the sky at night</li>
<li>During Sleeping Hours &ndash; most people are asleep (indoors, preoccupied, unable to watch the sky)</li>
</ul>


<p>So it makes perfect sense that most reported sightings are during &ldquo;Drinking Hours&rdquo;.  That also happens to be the time that its best to notice things in the sky and also the time when most people are able to be outside and focus on things outside of working or sleeping.  It&rsquo;s always interesting to me when a trusted publication like the Economist makes blatant errors in reporting and statistics &ndash; but goes to show analysis errors are all around us.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>See original article at <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21605918-everything-you-need-know-about-ufos-0">economist.com</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/images/blog_images/20140628_USM216_0.png" width="800" title="&#34;Economist UFO chart&#34;" alt="&#34;Economist UFO chart&#34;"></p>

<p>Image taken from <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21605918-everything-you-need-know-about-ufos-0">economist.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2014/06/27/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-27T17:45:58-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mirajsanghvi.com/blog/2014/06/27/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Hello, World!</strong>
Welcome to my blog.  This is something I&rsquo;ve been talking about doing for some time now &ndash; and so it feels really good to finally get it off the ground.  (Thank you Octopress for making it so easy!)  On this blog I hope to have an outlet for thoughts and ramblings I have.  Hopefully people read it and find it helpful &ndash; but honestly I mainly want to use this as a way to get better at writing out my thoughts.  Enjoy.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As for the subject areas I plan to cover &ndash; it really will be all over the place:</p>

<ul>
<li>news</li>
<li>technology</li>
<li>sports</li>
<li>san francisco</li>
<li>traveling</li>
<li>food/eating</li>
<li>coding</li>
<li>machine learning/statistics</li>
<li>advertising</li>
<li>anything else</li>
<li>the world</li>
</ul>


<p>As you can see, this is a rather expansive list&hellip;especially the last 2 &ndash; there really should be something for everyone.  So with that, let&rsquo;s get this started.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
